"Blue Collar" is the American Dream. If you're rich, you can buy
it. If you're anything else, you gotta fight for it.
Blue Collar is a drama, crime film directed by Paul Schrader.
Fed up with mistreatment at the hands of both management and union brass, and coupled with financial hardships on
each man's end, three auto assembly line workers hatch a plan to rob a safe at union headquarters.
Ezekiel 'Zeke' Brown, played by Richard Pryor.
Jerry Bartowski, played by Harvey Keitel.
Sam 'Smokey' James, played by Yaphet Kotto.
Bobby Joe, played by Ed Begley Jr..
Eddie Johnson, played by Harry Bellaver.
Jenkins, played by George Memmoli.
Blue Collar is a 1978 American crime drama film directed
by Paul Schrader in his directorial debut.
Written by Schrader and his brother Leonard, the film stars
Richard Pryor, Harvey Keitel and Yaphet Kotto.
The film is both a critique of union practices and an
examination of life in a working-class Rust Belt enclave.
Schrader, who wrote the script for Taxi Driver (1976), recalls the shooting as being very difficult because of
the artistic and personal tensions he had with the actors (including the stars themselves).
Schrader has also stated that while making the film, he suffered an on-set
mental breakdown, which made him seriously reconsider his career.
The film was shot in Detroit and Kalamazoo, Michigan.
The film explores themes of factory worker, robbery, blackmail, drinking, union.
The tone is emotional.